### POOJA BHANSALI

Sunnyvale, CA | 4088196624 | LinkedIn | Email Address

### **SUMMARY**

I am passionate in Business insights, Data Management, Data Integrity, Data Mining, Metrics & Reporting, Analyze Trends, Statistical Analysis, software as SPSS, SQL, Python, R, Excel, PowerBI, Tableau. Experience in providing analytical support to candidate issues through root-cause analysis. Strong in project management skills & Problem solving skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Business Operation Analyst, ZypMedia Inc, San Francisco CA — (02/2020 – 04/2020)

- Advanced Analytical data infrastructure to run ad-hoc operations, analyze KPIs, Marketing Campaigns pacing performance metrics.
- ♦ Build custom reporting and dashboards, fraud clicks, troubleshoot, track, measure, monitor, report, analyze data, and optimize marketing campaigns, Marketing Automation, improve workflow & delivery strategy to maximize reach to revenue growth.
- \* Tools; SOL (Redshift, Databricks), Microsoft Excel, VBA, Python, R, Trello, DataXu, Power BI, Datorama, Jira, Notion.

## Business Analyst, lettrs Ilc, New York — (12/2015 - 01/2017)

- ❖ Insight magnificent data-driven product conclusions using Mongodb and Campaign Facebook's integrated marketing ads.
- ❖ Lead in generating quick users' feedback on new feature Mobile Apps to improve efficiency to track record business metrics.
- ❖ Identify bugs (QA), collaborative with teams to test & resolve creative marketing dashboards and enrich impact end user open rate.

# Human Resources Intern (People Annalytics), Bombardier Transportation ltd, India — (09/2012-05/2013)

- ❖ Focus on employee records & maintain up-to-date employee holidays record and decision making in Excel, SAP, SPSS.
- ❖ Contributed training educating for recruiting ATS, Administration global change management system industry experience

### **EDUCATION**

- ❖ California State University, California: Master of Computer Science in Business Analytics, May 2020
- ❖ Maharaja Sayajirao University, India: Master's in Human Resources Management, May 2013
- Accounting), May 2011 Maharaja Sayajirao University, India: **Bachelors** in Commerce (Statistics & Accounting), May 2011

#### TOP TECHNICAL SKILLS

*Experience* in SQL (Mysql, RedShift), AWS, Python, R, SPSS, Ms Access, Excel(VBA, Pivot Tables, array functions, Power Pivots). *Expert* in Tableau, Google Analytics, PowerBI, Datorama, Dataxu, JMP (SAS), Statistical Analysis, Business Intelligence, Analytical Modeling, ETL, Data Collection, Data Warehouse, Quantitative Analysis, Data Pipeline, EMR, Kinesis, Business Metrics for Reporting.

### **RESEARCH PROJECTS**

## Database Foundation for University: LINK

- ❖ Develop physical integrity relational databases table schemas, product roadmap, loaded fully with complex Metadata warehouse.
- \* Attribution redundancies to 3NF & Enhanced entity relationship diagram, execution SOL queries, ERP, ETL, PHP, Tableau.

## Predicting Best Technical Company Based on Employees Reviews: LINK

❖ Perform end to end structured data gathering requirement, Extract data sources, manipulation, transformation data quality predicting model for Google, Apple, Netflix, Microsoft, Amazon, Facebook to help Business strategy, Machine Learning model accuracy by 87%.

### Business Analysis Strateay Data on Glassdoor Job Skills Sets: LINK

- ❖ Use Url to get to the APIs to collect data id allows to request job detail by skills and pull datasets integrity into JSON format.
- \* Data science to analyzing Data visualization large data sets, fetching employee data to gather business insights to employee job detail.
- ❖ Use Python, systems analysis, Pandas, Numpy, BeautifulSoup, matlab, Scikit-learn, scipy, TensorFlow, Matplotib, Pycharm, Seaborn.

#### Online eBay Auction Brand Business Performance: LINK

Analytic to execute strategic Analysis optimization: Linear regression, integer, simulation, queuing models in Excel Solver.

### Sentiment Data Analysis on letgo.com cars: LINK

Scrape data contain listing car sales operations on Big data - Hadoop Map Reduce, Quantitative Analyses; KNN, PCA, Naive Bayes.

# A model Chatbot - 'Vira' for Alaskan Airlines: LINK

- ❖ Chatbot has been developed with an intent to help Alaska airlines customers by answering covid-19 related questions.
- Chatbot have been tested with random questions, ensure accuracy regression Analysis, NLTK, tf-idf, cosine similarity, tkinter library.

### Gateway for Health Disease control and Prevention to help Clinical: LINK

❖ Data to implement Artificial Neural Network 89%, Decision Tree 87% models to classify the outcome of disease to help pregnant women grow to early detect diabetes, delivering prototype for diabetes risk prediction business requirement issues predicting modeling.